Guide to the Charles Barber papers related to Alexander Siloti M2112
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles Barber papers related to Alexander Siloti
1902-1942, 1977-2001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Barber, Charles
M2112
6 Linear Feet 5 boxes, 11 flat-boxes
Content Description
Research papers of Charles Barber for two of his publications on Alexander Siloti: Lost in the Stars (https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4807486) and The Alexander Siloti Collection (https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/5462577).
The materials include Charles Barber’s correspondence with Siloti family members, museums, archives and libraries, as well as published music scores, publications, newspaper clippings and research notes. Also included are photocopied and handwritten copies of Alexander Siloti’s correspondence as well as music scores, concert programs, posters, newspaper clippings and publications.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
Series 1: Research Materials. Series 2: Music Scores
Publication Rights
While Special Collections is the owner of the physical and digital items, permission to examine collection materials is not an authorization to publish. These materials are made available for use in research, teaching, and private study. Any transmission or reproduction beyond that allowed by fair use requires permission from the owners of rights, heir(s) or assigns.
Biographical / Historical
Alexander Siloti (1863-1945) was a Russian-born pianist, conductor and arranger. He studied at the Moscow Conservatory and after graduating went to Leipzig, Germany to study under Franz Liszt. Siloti taught at the Moscow Philharmonic and worked as an editor for Peter Ilich Tchaikovsky. He married Vera Tretyakova, the daughter of the industrialist Pavel Tretyakova and toured Europe and America with his wife and children from 1892-1900. He organized, financed, and conducted the Siloti Concerts in St Petersburg, introducing many important and influential musicians and composers. He was Intendant at the Mariinsky Theatre and briefly a teacher at the Petrograd Conservatory before fleeing from what had become the Soviet Union to Finland. Siloti eventually moved to America and taught at the Julliard School.
Throughout his life Siloti corresponded with many influential composers and others in the music world, such as Tchaikovsky and Liszt.
Dr. Charles Barber is a conductor active in concert, opera, and recordings, and a teacher in the history and aesthetics of conducting. Charles Barber earned a Bachelor of Music from the University of Victoria; Master of Arts from Stanford; and, Doctor of Musical Arts from Stanford. He was a student of the conductor Carlos Kleiber, and served in apprenticeship with the San Francisco Opera and the Metropolitan Opera. Barber was an assistant to composer and arranger Marty Paich working on recording projects and on films. He was a Visiting Assistant Professor at Stanford and created the Charles Barber Conductors on Film Collection (https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/10401369). He has served as a producer to Naxos Records, the world’s largest classical company, and in 1997 created American Classics, a series that has now over 300 CDs in release. Barber has conducted in Canada and the United States, and on tour in South Korea, Singapore, Japan, Morocco and Spain. He has served as the Conductor and Artistic Director of the City Opera Vancouver, Canada.
Charles Barber corresponded with Kyriena Siloti, Alexander Siloti’s daughter and with Maria Siloti, who married Siloti’s son Levko Siloti and studied piano under Siloti, as well as with other Siloti family members. He also wrote to museums, archives, universities and libraries in the United States, the United Kingdom, the Russian Federation/Soviet Union and Germany to find materials related to Siloti.
Concert programs; Piano music; Musical scores.; Pianists; Barber, Charles; Siloti, Alexander, 1863-1945; Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich; Liszt, Franz; Chopin, Frédéric; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943
- Series 1: Research Materials, 1922, 1971-2001
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents Charles Barber’s research for his books about Alexander Siloti. The materials include Charles Barber’s correspondence with Siloti family members, museums, archives and libraries, as well as research notes, newspaper clippings, publications and music sheets. Also included are photocopied and handwritten copies of Alexander Siloti’s correspondence as well as music sheets, concert programs, posters, newspaper clippings and publications about Alexander Siloti.
  The files in this series have been kept in their original order with mostly original folder headings.
  - Alexander Siloti programs (1890-1912), 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of music sheets, programs and posters from concerts Siloti organized in Russia. Also includes Charles Barber correspondence, research and notebooks. The languages include: English, Russian, German, Dutch and French.
  - Mikhail Glinka's, L'Alouette, arranged by Alexander Siloti, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence and a photocopy of the original sheet music.
  - Alexander Siloti correspondence, handwritten copies by Maria Siloti (1892-1924), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Siloti CD Project, 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photocopies for research on Alexander Siloti (1995-1999) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes Charles Barber correspondence and photocopies of publications about Alexander Siloti.
  - Siloti Concert Programs (1903-1913), transcribed by Maria Siloti, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Siloti Concert Programs (1913-1917), transcribed by Maria Siloti, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Levko (Koshka) Siloti and Maria (Mussy, Mary), Siloti, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Levko Alexandrovich Siloti was Alexander Siloti's youngest son. He married Mary Alberta Mueller (Maria, Mussy) who studied piano with Siloti. Materials include correspondence and an excerpt from a manuscript Maria wrote about their life.
  - Russian book on Alexander Siloti (1963), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - CB/BH Music, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Materials include correspondence and publication list. CB/BH Music was a company formed by Charles Barber and Bruce Herman.
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Siloti Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Siciliano, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Siloti Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Prelude in B Minor, BWV 855a, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Siloti Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Prelude to Cantata 29, BWV 29, orchestra score and parts, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Siloti Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Brandenburg Concerto No. 5, BWV 1050, orchestra score and parts, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Siloti Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Siloti Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Organ Prelude in E Minor, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Silot Editions, Sergei Rachmaninoff, Romanze Op. 8, No. 2, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Silot Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Gigue, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Silot Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Prelude from Cantata No. 29, BWV 29 for piano in E Major, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Silot Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Prelude from Cantata No. 29, BWV 29 for piano in D Major, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Silot Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Organ Prelude in G Minor, BWV 535, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Silot Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Chaconne, BWV 1004a, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Silot Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Air, BWV 1068, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Silot Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Prelude, BWV 1010, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Silot Editions, Johann Sebastian Bach, Adagio, BWV 1018, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Siloti Editions extras, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - CB/BH Music Alexander Siloti Editions, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Research Materials (1901-1998), 1986-1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Materials include correspondence, posters, concert programs and photocopies of publications and articles from archives, museums and libraries in the United States, Britain, Germany and Russia. There is also Charles Barber correspondence with these institutions. Languages include English, Russian, German and French.
  - Miscellaneous Research Materials (1901-1998), 1986-1998 (Flat-box 16, Folder 1)
  - Siloti book, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Materials include index cards, research notes, cards from catalog and photocopies of publications. Languages are in English and Russian.
  - Articles (1892-1998) (part 1 of 2), 1989-1998 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Photocopies of publications, magazines and journals. Also includes Charles Barber correspondence. Languages are in German, French, English and Russian.
  - Articles (1892-1998) (part 2 of 2), 1989-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography (1940-1983), undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of publications with annotations and notes by Charles Barber. Languages include German and English.
  - Catalogues, 1971-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1985-2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Charles Barber correspondence with archives, museums and libraries regarding materials on Alexander Siloti.
  - Biographical Dictionary of Russian/Soviet Composers (1989), 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Research materials on Paul Dukes (1922-1967), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Family trees (1921), 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Film, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Research materials on Alexei Haieff, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Rud. Ibach Sohn (1885), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Materials include Charles Barber correspondence and photocopies of Alexander Siloti materials from the Rud. Ibach Sohn archives. Rud. Ibach Sohn is a German company that manufactures pianos.
  - International Piano Archive at the University of Maryland College Park, 1986-1998 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Julliard School Archives (1920-1947, 1990), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Leipziger Städische Bibliotheken Msikbibliothek (1883-1910), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Libraries (1924-1937), 1985-1998 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Research materials on Franz Liszt (1934), 1995 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Pierpont Morgan Library (1903-1931), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Naxos/Encore Liner Notes - Marco Polo, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Permissions, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Publishers, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Research materials on Sergei Rachmaninoff, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Alexander Siloti Archive (1898-1911, undated), 1922, 1987-1997 (Flat-box 16, Folder 2)
  - Alexander Siloti Archive (1898-1911, undated), 1922, 1987-1997 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Siloti Recital Programs (1892-1981), 1988-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Recordings (1924-1927), 1986-1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes Charles Barber correspondence and research notes. Also includes photocopies of publications and liner notes from Siloti's recordings.
  - Alex Siloti: correspondence, 1986-1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence between Charles Barber and Alex Siloti, Alexander Siloti's grandson.
  - Kyriena Siloti, 1986-1998 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Includes Charles Barber research notes and correspondence with Kyriena Siloti. Kyriena Siloti was Alexander Siloti's daughter.
  - My Memories of Liszt by Alexander Siloti, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Maria Siloti: corresondence, 1986-1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Siloti's students' questionnaires, 1986-1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Includes correspondence and questionnaires for students who studied piano under Alexander Siloti.
  - Sources, 1986-1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Stanford research grant, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Peter Ilich Tchaikovsky (1886-1893), 1993-1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Photocopies and handwritten copies of correspondence between Tchaikovsky and Siloti. Also includes correspondence between Maria Siloti and Charles Barber. Materials are in Russian and English.
  - Writing notes, 1986-1998 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series 2: Music Scores, 1902-1942, undated
  Series 2: Series 2 consists of published and manuscript music scores, mainly from Alexander Siloti, Levko Siloti or Maria Siloti’s music collection of major composers including, Arensky, Bach, Balakirev, Chopin, Liszt, Rachmaninoff, Rubinstein and Tchaikovsky. Many of the scores are annotated.
  The series is in original order and is arranged alphabetically by composer and by title. It contains a mixture of originals and photocopies. Some of the scores also include correspondence from Maria Siloti to Charles Barber explaining the importance or context of a particular score with regards to Alexander Siloti.
  - Arensky, An der Quelle, undated (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence from Maria Siloti, undated
  - Arensky, Basso Ostinato (photocopy), (1898) (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
  - Arensky, Consolation (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
  - Arensky, Logaedes (photocopy), (1898) (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
  - Arensky, Six Caprices pour Piano, # 2,3,4,6 (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
  - Arensky, Valse Nuit d’Egypte (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bach, Adagio From the Toccato C Major, for Organ BWV 564 arr. Cello/piano (photcopy), (1925) (Flat-box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bach, Adagio A-Moll BWV 564 (handwritten, photopcopy), (undated) (Flat-box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bach, Air (Alexander Siloti Concert Repertoire Booklet) Suite #3, 1927 (Flat-box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bach, Air (Alexander Siloti Concert Repertoire Booklet) Suite #3, 1927 (Flat-box 6, Folder 10)
  - Bach, Air BWV 1068 arr. String quartet (handwritten, photocopy), (1920) (Flat-box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bach, Air (extrait de la suite d’orchestre en re) arr. Cello/piano (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bach, Air on G String (photocopy), (1927) (Flat-box 6, Folder 13)
    Includes correspondence from Maria Siloti, 1987
  - Bach, Air arr. Violin/piano (handwritten, large photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 6, Folder 14)
  - Bach, Andante (From the Sonata for Violin Solo in C Major) No. 3, 1927 (Flat-box 6, Folder 15)
  - Bach, Andante aus dem 5 Brandenburg’schen Konzert, violin & Violo, piano (some pages separated, heavily taped edge), 1921 (Flat-box 6, Folder 16)
  - Bach, Andante (from the “Italian Concerto” for Piano) (handwritten), undated (Flat-box 6, Folder 17)
  - Bach, Andante BWV 1003 arr. Violin & viola, piano, 1927 (Flat-box 6, Folder 18)
  - Bach, Andante aus dem 5. Brandenburg’schen Konzert, BWV 1050 (photocopy), (1921) (Flat-box 6, Folder 19)
  - Bach, Chaconne BWV 1004, arr. Vln or cello/piano (photocopy), (1924) (Flat-box 6, Folder 20)
  - Bach, Choral Prelude (I Call On Thee Lord), 1936 (Flat-box 6, Folder 21)
  - Bach, Choral Prelude (“ich ruf’zu dir, Herr Jesu Christ”, for the organ) (handwritten), undated (Flat-box 6, Folder 22)
    Includes excerpt from Levko and Maria Siloti's autobiography
  - Bach, Choral Prelude Cello Part Revised by P. Casals (handwritten), undated (Flat-box 6, Folder 23)
  - Bach, Concert No. 2 in E Major for violin and orchestra (Brandenburg) (annotations in red pencil), 1924 (Flat-box 6, Folder 24)
  - Bach, Concert No. 2 (mi majeur) pour violon et orchestra (Brandenburg), 1921 (Flat-box 6, Folder 25)
  - Bach, Concerto in D major (Brandenburg Concerto No. 5) for Piano, Flute, Violin, undated (Flat-box 6, Folder 26)
  - Bach, Concerto in D major (Brandenburg Concerto No. 5) for Piano, Flute, Violin, undated (Flat-box 6, Folder 27)
  - Bach, Erstes Konzert I, 1915 (Flat-box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bach, Erstes Konzert II, 1915 (Flat-box 7, Folder 2)
  - Bach, Gigue (from the Piano – Suite B major), 1923 (Flat-box 7, Folder 3)
  - Bach, Koncert fur Klavier in D Dur; piano part, undated (Flat-box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bach, Koncert fur Klavier in D Dur; piano part, undated (Flat-box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bach, Italian Concerto, arr. Piano 4-hands, 1930 (Flat-box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bach, Organ Prelude (E Minor), 1923 (Flat-box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bach, Organ Prelude (E Minor), 1923 (Flat-box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bach, Organ Prelude (G Minor), 1924 (Flat-box 7, Folder 9)
  - Bach, Organ Toccata and Fugue in D minor (pencil annotations), undated (Flat-box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bach, Paraphrase on the Prelude in C# Minor, 1924 (Flat-box 7, Folder 11)
  - Bach, Passacaglia c-moll fur Orgel (pencil annotations), undated (Flat-box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bach, Prelude aus der Kantate No. 29, undated (Flat-box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bach, Prelude aus dem Clavier-Buchlein fur Wilhem Friedemann Bach (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bach, Prelude (from the Cantata # 29) (handwritten, photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bach, Prelude (cantata 29, BWV 29) D minor, 1909 (Flat-box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bach, Prelude aus der Kantate No. 29 (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bach, Siciliano, undated (Flat-box 8, Folder 6)
  - Bach, Siciliano (aus der Sonata fur clavier und Flate) (handwritten), undated (Flat-box 8, Folder 7)
  - Bach, Siciliano (handwritten with black and red ink), undated (Flat-box 8, Folder 8)
  - Bach, Siciliano BWV 1031 (handwritten, photocopy), undated (Flat-box 8, Folder 9)
  - Bach, Sonate (I,II,III, e V) piano e violin; vln only (handwritten), undated (Flat-box 8, Folder 10)
  - Bach, Sonata for vln solo, E major; arr. Organ and chamber players (incomplete) (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 8, Folder 11)
  - Bach, Sonate III (E major) for violin and piano (handwritten), undated (Flat-box 8, Folder 12)
  - Bach, Sonate VI (pencil annotations), undated (Flat-box 8, Folder 13)
  - Bach, Toccata and Fugue D Minor (handwritten), undated (Flat-box 8, Folder 14)
  - Bach, Toccata and Fugue in D Minor BWV 565 (handwritten, photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 8, Folder 15)
  - Bach, Toccata and Fugue, D Minor for Organ, BWV 565 (handwritten, photocopy), undated (Flat-box 16, Folder 3)
  - Balakirev, Au jardin, 1906 Balakirev, Berceuse pour le Piano, undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 1)
  - Balakirev, Islamey Fantaisie Orientale, 1926 (Flat-box 9, Folder 2)
  - Balakirev, Islamey Fantaisie Orientale, 1926 (Flat-box 9, Folder 3)
  - Balakirev, Islamey Fantaisie Orientale (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 9, Folder 4)
  - Balakirev, L’Alouette, undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 5)
  - Balakirev, L’Alouette (handwritten), undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 6)
  - Balakirev, Nocturne pour Piano, undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 7)
  - Balakirev, Novelette pour le Piano, 1906 (Flat-box 9, Folder 8)
  - Beethoven, Sonaten Fur Klavier, undated (Flat-box 16, Folder 4)
  - Beethoven, 32 Variationen fur das Pianoforte (pencil annotations), undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 9)
  - Bizet, Carmen, undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
  - Bizet, Carmen 3-me entr’acte, 1919 (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
  - Bizet, Carmen 3-me entr’acte, 1919 (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
  - Bizet, Glinka (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 9, Folder 13)
  - Borodin, For the Shores…Native Land, undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 14)
  - Borodin, Serenade (from “Petite Suite”) (photocopy), (1926) (Flat-box 9, Folder 15)
  - Brahms, Variationen uber ein Thema von Robert Schumann (pencil annotations), undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 16)
  - Chopin, Ballade G Minor Op. 23 (notes glued in), undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 17)
  - Chopin, Ballade G-minor Op. 23, undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 18)
  - Chopin, Etude E flat minor #6 Op. 10 (notes glued in) (some handwritten notes), undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 19)
  - Chopin, Etude F Minor Op. 25 #10 (notes glued in) (some handwritten notes), undated (Flat-box 9, Folder 20)
  - Chopin, Etude No. 25 in F Minor (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 9, Folder 21)
  - Chopin, Etude No. 25 F Minor, 1929 (Flat-box 9, Folder 22)
  - Chopin, Nocturne D flat major Op. 27 No. 2 (notes glued in) (pencil annotations), undated (Flat-box 10, Folder 1)
  - Chopin, Nocturne Op. 27 No. 2 (pencil and ink annotations), undated (Flat-box 10, Folder 2)
  - Chopin, Nocturne Op. 48 No. 1 C Minor, 1929 (Flat-box 10, Folder 3)
  - Chopin, Nocturne C Minor Op. 48 No. 1 (handwritten), undated (Flat-box 10, Folder 4)
  - Chopin, Pianoforte-Werke Band 5. Polonaisen, undated (Flat-box 10, Folder 5)
  - Chopin, Prelude Op. 28, No. 3, G Major, 1929 (Flat-box 10, Folder 6)
  - Chopin, Prelude Op. 28 No. 3 G Major (handwritten, photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 10, Folder 7)
  - Chopin, Scherzo #3 (handwritten) (notes glued in) (pencil and ink annotations), undated (Flat-box 10, Folder 8)
  - Chopin, Sonate mit Cello (handwritten and printed), undated (Flat-box 10, Folder 9)
  - Chopin, Walzer (Edition Schott NR: 21), 1917 (Flat-box 10, Folder 10)
  - Dohnanyi, Sechs Konzertetuden Heft I, 1923 (Flat-box 10, Folder 11)
  - Dohnanyi, Vier Rhapsodien, nr. I, IV, 1930 (Flat-box 10, Folder 12)
  - Glazunov, Serenade du Troubadour Op. 79, undated (Flat-box 10, Folder 13)
  - Glazunov, Volga Boatmen’s Song, 1926 (Flat-box 10, Folder 14)
  - Gluck, Orpheus 2nd Ballet (handwritten, photocopy), undated (Flat-box 10, Folder 15)
  - Handel, Dettingen Te Deum and photocopy, undated (Flat-box 10, Folder 16)
  - Ibert, Escales No. 11, 1924 (Flat-box 11, Folder 1)
  - Kreisler, Praeludium and Allegro, 1910 (Flat-box 11, Folder 2)
  - Lyadov, Goolenki, 1927 (Flat-box 11, Folder 3)
  - Lyadov, Prelude Op. 11 No. 1, undated (Flat-box 11, Folder 4)
  - Lyadov, Prelude Op. 11 No. 1 (handwritten, photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 11, Folder 5)
  - Lyadov, Variations sur un theme de Glinka (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 11, Folder 6)
    Includes correspondence from Maria Siloti, 1987. Also includes photocopies of telegrams from 1935 and 1939.
  - Liszt, Abscheid (Farewell) (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 11, Folder 7)
  - Liszt, Annees de Pelerinage 1re Annee: Suisse, 1917 (Flat-box 11, Folder 8)
  - Liszt, Au bord d’une source (Annees de Pelerinage, Ire annee), 1923 (Flat-box 11, Folder 9)
  - Liszt, Au lac de Wallenstadt (Annees de Pelerinage, I, No. 2), 1926 (Flat-box 11, Folder 10)
  - Liszt, Annees de Pelerinage 2de Annee VII. Apres une Lecture du Dante (pencil annotations), 1909 (Flat-box 11, Folder 11)
  - Liszt, Ballade #2 G Minor (some notes glued in) (pencil and ink annotations), undated (Flat-box 11, Folder 12)
  - Liszt, Benediction De Dieu…Solitude (photocopy), (1923) (Flat-box 11, Folder 13)
  - Liszt, Benediction De Dieu…Solitude (ink annotations), 1923 (Flat-box 11, Folder 14)
  - Liszt, Concert Etude (D flat major) (pencil annotations), 1931 (Flat-box 11, Folder 15)
  - Liszt, Concert Etude (D flat major) (pencil annotations), 1931 (Flat-box 11, Folder 16)
  - Liszt, Concert Pathetique (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
  - Liszt, Concert Pathetique (handwritten, photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 16, Folder 5)
  - Rachmaninoff, Romanze (op. 8, No. 2) fur pianoforte (photocopy), (1899) (Flat-box 16, Folder 6)
  - Tchaikovsky, Concert (No. 1, B moll) (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 16, Folder 7)
  - Liszt, Concerto No. 1 in E Major, 1904 (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
  - Liszt, Concerto Pathetique I (E moll-E minor-Mi mineur), undated (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
  - Liszt, Concerto Pathetique II (E moll-E minor-Mi mineur), undated (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
  - Liszt, Danse Macabre, 1911 (Flat-box 12, Folder 5)
  - Liszt, Danse Macabre Totentanz, 1911 (Flat-box 12, Folder 6)
  - Liszt, Dante Sonata (photocopy), (1904) (Flat-box 12, Folder 7)
    Includes correspondence from Maria Siloti, 1986
  - Liszt, Dreams of Love (lots of pencil markings, lyrics in the beginning scratched out), undated (Flat-box 12, Folder 8)
  - Liszt, Erstes Concert Kleine Flote (photocopy), (undated) (Flat-box 12, Folder 9)